Oh, boy.
好家伙的
What?
咋了?
********
在不违反"我不得批评你的工作"
协议之下 我无法做出评价
Then what was "Oh, boy"?
那干吗说"好家伙的"?
Great restraint on my part.
已经是极度的克制了
There's nothing wrong
with the science here.
我的科学工作又没错
Perhaps you mean a different thing
than I do when you say, "Science."
也许你说的"科学"和我认为的
是完全两码事
Okay, how's that?
好吧 现在呢?
You actually had it
right in the first place.
实际上一开始你就是对的
Once again, you've fallen
for one of my classic pranks.
你又被我给忽悠了一把
Bazinga!
砰玟!(泡泡龙游戏里的声音)
Now here's a peculiar e-mail.
这邮件不多见啊
The president of the university wants me to meet
him at his office tomorrow morning at 8:00 a.m.
校长要我明天早上八点
去一趟他的办公室
- Why?
- It doesn't say. It must be an emergency.
- 为啥?
- 没说啊 肯定有急事
Everyone at the university knows I eat
breakfast at 8:00 and move my bowels at 8:20.
学校里每个人都知道我八点吃早餐
八点二十开始做肠道运动
Yes, how did we live before Twitter?
没错 没有Twitter之前我们是怎么活的?
I guess you'll find out
what it is in the morning.
我想你明天早上就会知道了
That's 14 hours away.
那还有14个钟头呢
For the next 840 minutes, I'm
effectively one of Heisenberg's particles;
在接下来的840分钟里
我就是海森堡的一颗微粒
(德国物理学家 量子力学创始人之一)
I know where I am or I know how fast
I'm going, but I can't know both.
我要么只知道自己在哪儿
要么只知道自己有多快
Yet how am I supposed to carry on with this
huge annoying thing hovering over my head?
这么件烦人的事儿在我脑海盘旋
我这要怎么活下去?
Yeah, I know the feeling.
是啊 感同身受
-=http://sfile.ydy.com=-
proudly presents
-=伊甸园美剧http://sfile.ydy.com=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=http://sfile.ydy.com=-
sync:咔肉肉
-=YTET-伊甸园字幕组=-
翻译: 饭特稀 Dr.Agon 冰啤梨果橙
校对: penny
时间轴: 咔肉肉
双语:徐小帆
The Big Bang
Theory Season02 Episode23
天才理论传
第二季 第23集
Leonard? Leonard? Leonard?
Leonard Leonard Leonard
Sheldon, it's 2:00 in the morning.
Sheldon 现在是凌晨2点
Why is everybody keep
telling me what time it is?
为啥大伙儿都告知我现在几点?
Everybody?
大伙儿?
You, the president of the university,
his wife, their sullen teenage daughter.
你 校长 他妻子
还有他们闷闷不乐的小女儿
That entire family is fascinated by what
time it is and whether people know it.
他们一家子都像着了魔似的
关注时间生怕别人不知道
You went to President Seibert's
house in the middle of the nig?
你大半夜的跑到Seibert校长家去了?
He didn't respond to my e-mail,
his phone number is unlisted.
他没回我的邮件 我也没他电话号码
Tell me what my other option was.
我还有其他选择么
You could have waited until morning.
你可以等到明天早上啊
I know, look who I'm talking to.
我知道 又是鸡同鸭讲
Do you remember the grant proposal I
submitted to the National Science Foundation
还记得我提交给国家科学
基金会的拨款提议吗?
to detect slow-moving monopoles
at the magnetic North Pole?
用来检测北极缓慢移动的磁单极
Hardly a day goes by when
I don't think about it.
只要不想这事 日子都没发过
Aw, how nice.
嗷 真棒啊
Well, a space opened up at the last minute
on the NSF expedition to the Arctic Circle.
国科基金会极地科考队
在最后一刻出现一个空位
Wait a minute.
等等
- He offered to send you to the North Pole?
- Yes.
- 他要把你送去北极?
- 是的
In fact, he was quite enthusiastic.
事实上 他还相当热心呢
He said, "Frankly, if I could
send you tonight, I would."
他说"坦白讲 如果今晚就能
把你送过去 我绝不犹豫"
Okay, well, do you want to go?
那好啊 你想去么?
Of course not. I'm a
theoretical physict.
当然不想了 我是个理论物理学家
A career I chose in no small
part because it's indoors,
我选择这个职业主要是因为
它是室内工作
but if I'm able to detect
slow-moving magnetic monopoles there,
要是我能去北极探测
缓慢移动的磁单极的话
I will be the scientis
to confirm string theory.
我会成为确认弦理论的人了
People will write books about me.
人们会为我著书立传
Third-graders will create macaroni-art
dioramas depicting scenes from my life.
三年级的小盆友们会用通心粉
作透视画来描绘我的生活
Sure, maybe a tableau of me
trying to pummel you to death.
没错 也许是我玩命把你打死的生动场面
- Sarcasm?
- Maybe.
- 讽刺?
- 也许
I'm on the horns of a dilemma.
我可真是进退两难啊
Can you imagine me, Sheldon
Cooper, at the North Pole?
你能想象我 Sheldon Cooper
在北极的情景么?
Easy peasy, I'm doing it right now.
小菜啦 我正在想象呢
I'm not good with cold, Leonard.
Leonard 我可怕冷了
How often have we had
to leave a movie theater
我们有多少次从电影院里逃出来
because I got a headache from
drinking the Icee too fast?
就因为我喝冰吸太猛导致头疼了
- I can't go.
- Well, then don't go.
- 我没法去
- 那就别去咯
How can you say that?
这话你也说得出口?
The scientific opportunity of a lifetime presents
itself and my best friend says "Don't go."
终生难遇的科研机会出现在眼前
可我最好的朋友劝我说"别去"
- All right, then go.
- Listen to you.
- 好吧 那去咯
- 你听听
How can I possibly go?
我怎么能去呢?
Sheldon, what are the words I can say right now to
end this conversation and let me go back to sleep?
Sheldon 我要说什么你才肯罢休
放我回去睡觉哇?
Odd, President Seibert posed
the exact same question.
奇怪 Seibert校长也是这么问我的
- How was it resolved?
- It wasn't.
- 怎么解决的?
- 没解决啊
His wife set their dogs on me
and rendered the question moot.
他妻子把他们家的狗放了出来
导致这个问题最终悬而未决
Just imagi. If he says yes, we'll
have an entire summer without Sheldon.
你想想 如果他答应了
我们就一夏天不用对着Sheldon了
We could play outside.
可以出去玩
We could sit on the
left side of the couch.
可以坐在沙发左边儿
I could use the bathroom at 8:20.
我可以在八点二十上厕所
Our dreams are very small, aren't they?
我们的梦想还真够小的 不是吗?
Good news, gentlemen, I
have tentatively accepted...
好消息 我暂时同意了...
Yeah!
好耶!
the invitation to join
the Arctic Expedition.
加入极地科考队的邀请
- It's not gonna be the same without you.
- Godspeed.
- 我们会想念你的
- 祝你好运
Thank you, but your
sentiments may be premature.
多谢 不过你们情绪释放的太早了
Ooh, I don't like where this is going.
噢 我有不祥的预感
I would like to propose...
我建议...
that the three of you accompany me.
让你们仨陪我一起去
To the North Pole?
去北极?
Yes.
是的
Is this just so we won't touch
your stuff while you're away?
是为了防止你不在时 我们碰你东西?
I'll admit that was a concern.
我承认这是顾虑之一
But the fact is, I'll
need a support team.
但实情是 我需要一支支援小队
- And the three of you are my first choice.
- Really?
- 你们仨则是我的首选
- 真的假的?
Well, there are others who
might be more qualified,
也许有其他人更加胜任
but the thought of interviewing
them gave me a stomachache.
可一想到要给他们面试我就胃疼
Now, I know I'm proposing
an enormous undertaking,
我知道这是件大事
so why don't you take a
few moments discuss it?
你们几个何不花点时间商量一下?
We're not really gonna go to
the North Pole with him, are we?
我们该不会真跟他去北极吧?
I'm still within earshot!
我还听得见噢!
You may want to wait
for my door to close.
你们可以等我关了门再说
We're not really gonna go to
the North Pole with him, are we?
我们该不会真跟他去北极吧?
Hang on. Let's talk about it.
等等 我们先商量一下呗
This is a National Science
Foundation expedition.
这是国家科学基金会的科考队
I don't know how we can turn it down.
我不知道怎么可能拒绝
Easy. Instead of saying, "No, we
don't want to go on an NSF expedition,"
好办啊 不要说"不 我们不想
参加国科会的科考队"
say, "No, we don't want to spend "three months stuck
in a cabin in the Arctic Circle with an anal nutbag."
要说"不 我们不想和疯子
在极地小屋待三个月"
But if we were part of the team
that confirmed string theory,
但如果我们成了确认弦理论的人
we could drink for free in
any bar in any college town
我们在有更强科研项目的大学的
with a university that has
a strong science program.
大学城里的任何酒吧喝个够
Howard, this is big science.
Howard 这是重大的科学问题
You could be the engineer who builds the
equipment that puts us on the ver of magazines.
你制作的设备能让我们大家都
成为杂志的封面人物
I could also be the engineer who
builds the crossbow that kills Sheldon.
我制作的十字弓也能杀了Sheldon
You still might get on a magazine.
你还是会上杂志封面
- So you guys are seriously considering this?
- Yes.
- 你们还真在考虑了?
- 没错
And you think you can
put up with Sheldon?
你们可以忍受Sheldon?
Well, I'm a Hindu.
我是印度人
My religion teaches that if we suffer
in this life we are rewarded in the next.
我的宗教说如果我们这一世受苦
下一世会得到回报的
Three months at the
North Pole with Sheldon,
和Sheldon在北极呆三个月
and I'm reborn as a well-hung
billionaire with wings!
我就能转世投胎成一个
长翅膀的大乓谕蚋晃塘!
Well, gentlemen, have
you reached a decision?
先生们 你们做好决定了吗?
- I'm in.
- Me too.
- 我去
- 我也是
Oh, damn it. Peer pressure. Fine.
哦 该死 压力好大哦 好吧
Excellent.Just an FYI, as I am
the expedition's team leader,
很好 告诉你们哈
因为我是科考队的队长
protocol dictates that
be phrased, "Fine, sir."
注意说话礼节 "好的 长官"
But don't worry, there
will be a briefing.
但不用担心 会给你们简报的
- Penny.
- Sheldon.
- Penny
- Sheldon
- Pey.
- Sheldon.
- Penny
- Sheldon
- Penny.
- Sheldon.
- Penny
- Sheldon
- Penny.
- Sheldon.
- Penny
- Sheldon
- Penny!
- Sheldon!
Penny!
What do you want?
你想干嘛?
I need access to the Cheesecake
Factory's walk-in freezer.
我要用奶酪蛋糕工厂的冷冻仓库
Now, honey, I already told you, the hamburger
meat is fresh and stored at a safe temperature.
哦 宝贝 我都告诉过你了 汉堡肉
储藏在安全温度下 很新鲜
No. This is to train for a three-moh
expedition to the magnetic North Pole.
不 这是为了去北极三月科考训练
What?
啥?
I don't know how that sentence
could possibly confuseou...
我不知道这句话你咋就不懂呢...
but to elaborate, I'm going to the Arctic
Circle with Leonard, Wolowitz and Koothrappali.
但还是要解释一下 我要和Leonard
Wolowitz和Koothrappali去北极圈
- You're all going?
- Yes.
- 你们都去?
- 对
- For three months?
- Yes.
- 去三个月?
- 对
Excuse me.
失陪一下
Is that a yes or a no on the freezer?
冷冻库到底让不让我用啊?
The woman has the
attention span of a gnat.
这女人注意力咋就集中不起来
Hey, Leonard. Sheldon says
you're going to the North Pole.
嘿 Leonard Sheldon说你要去北极
Yeah. Pretty cool, huh?
对 很酷 对吧?
Yeah. I'm just a little
surprised you didn't tell me.
对 只是你没告诉我 我有点吃惊
Oh, well, it all happened kind of fast.
哦 这一切发生的有点突然
And we had to get physicals and buy thermal
underwear and study up on, you know, snow and stuff.
我们得做体检 买保暖内衣
研究一下 你知道 雪之类的东西
Sorry, I was gonna tell you.
对不起嘛 我本来是要告诉你的
Oh, hey, no, you don't
have to apologize.
哦 嘿 不 你不用道歉啊
There's no reason you have to tell
me. I was just... you know, surprised.
你也没必要告诉我啊
我只是...对吧 吃惊
Yes, yes, you were busy, you were
surprised, all very fascinating.
对 对 你很忙 你很吃惊
都很有意思
Now where do we stand on the freezer?
冷冻库的事到底咋说?
Is he serious?
他说真的?
Actually, it would help.
其实吧 会有帮助的
All right, I'll see what I can do.
好吧 我来看看我能做点什么吧
So, three months at the Nth Pole.
说来 在北极呆三个月
- Wow, that is... awesome.
- Yeah.
- 哇 这...太棒了
- 是啊
I'm sorry, but at what point do you put
this see what you can do plan into action?
对不起 但你啥时候能把
"看看能做点什么"付诸于实践呢?
Just a warning, Sheldon-- The
freezer locks from the outside.
警告你一下 Sheldon...
冷冻库的门可是从外上锁的
- Did she seem upset to you?
- No.
- 你说她有不爽吗?
- 没
- Did she seem upset to you?
- No.
- 你说她有不爽吗?
- 没
Oh, good, I got it right.
哦 好的 我猜对了
Are you upset?
你心里不爽?
- A little bit.
- Two for two. I'm on fire.
- 有点
- 又对一题 百发百中啊
I mean, I know she's not
my girlfriend or anything,
我是说 我知道她不是我女友啥的
but wouldn't you thinkshe'd feel a little bad
that I'm going to be gone for the whole summer?
但你觉得我整个夏天都不在
她会不会有一点难过呢?
That feels like a bonus question.
这好像是个附加问题啊
I'm going to stop here while I'm
ahead, but I've had a great time.
我比分领先所以我先闪啦
但我玩的很开心哦
All right, the purpose of this drill
好的 这次训练的目的
is to acclimate us to the use
otools in extreme temperatures
是让我们适应在恶劣的温度下
运用各种工具
such as we will face
in the Arctic Circle.
这与我们要在北极面对的环境一样
- Where are your tools?
- Right here.
- 你的工具呢?
- 在这
All right, team, open
up your practice kits.
好的 队员们
打开你们的练习工具包
As the university did not permit
me to bring the actual equipment
由于学校不允许我拿真正的装备
we'll be using to the
Cheesecake Factory,
来奶酪蛋糕工厂
because apparently, I'm "ridiculous,"
因为很显然 我很"可笑"
I've provided substitutes which
will exercise your fine motor skills.
我提供了一些替代品
来训练你们的运动技巧
Leonard, you will be doing a series
of complex mathematical problems
Leonard 你要做一系列
复杂的数学题
on a vintage Casio model 1175
calculator watch I received
用一个过时的卡西欧
1175型计算手表
when I won the Earth
Science medal in 3rd grade.
这是我三年级赢得
地球科学奖章时得到的
Treat it with respect.
好好用它
Raj, you will be painting
sideburns and a Van Dyke
Raj 你要给一个六英尺的
莱格拉斯精灵模型
on a six-inch figurine
of Legolas the elf.
画连鬓胡和短尖胡须
Now, remember, a Van Dyke is
a goatee without a mustache.
要记住短尖胡须是
下巴上的胡子 嘴唇上没有
Wolowitz, you will be completing a
series of delicate surgical procedures
Wolowitz 你要用
经典儿童玩具"手术"
on the classic children's
game "Operation."
完成一系列精细的手术程序
To begin with, you will remove
funny bone for two hundred dollars.
首先 200美元移除肘部尺骨端
For this I went to MIT.
就是因为这个我进的麻省理工
And begin.
开始
I think I swallowed some paint!
我想我吞掉了一些颜料!
I can't press any of the
buttons with my gloves.
戴着手套我根本不能按按键
Oh, son of a bitch!
哦 狗娘养的!
Adversity is to be expected. Continue.
这些困难我们会遇到的 继续
Oh, boy, am I gonna get sued.
哦 天啊 我要被起诉了
- Okay, I can't do this.
- Me either.
- 好吧 我做不来这个
- 我也是
Gentlemen, use your
imagination. Innovate.
先生们 发挥你们的想象力 创新
Did Han Solo let Luke Skywalker freeze
to death on the ice planet of Hoth? No.
汉索罗有没有让卢克天行者
在霍斯星球上冻死呢? 没有
He cut open a tauntaun and used its
internal body heat to warm him up.
他把一个驼驼切开
用它体内的热量来取暖
You heard the man. Hold him
down and I'll cut him open.
你们也听到了 把他按住
我来把他切开
Hang on, I know I don't
possess the tools of leadership,
等一下 我知道我不是领导
but I don't understand why we can't assemble the
equipment inside the hut and then take it outside.
但我不懂我们为什么不能在屋里
装好设备 然后再拿到屋外
I hadn't thought of that.
这我倒没想过
I guess we're done here.
我看可以收工了
Here, drink slash eat this.
给 吃掉喝掉这个
What is it?
这是啥?
Hot chocolate with a stick of butter.
黄油棒加热巧克力
Okay, why?
好的 为什么?
Because in the frigid
temperatures in the Arctic,
因为在北极严酷的温度下
we need to consume at least 5,000 calories
a day just to maintain our body weight.
只是为了保持体重 我们一天
至少要消耗5000卡的热量
Sheldon, you know I can't eat
butter. I'm lactose intolerant.
Sheldon 你知道我不能吃黄油的
我不耐乳糖
Way ahead of you, that's an I
Can't Believe It's Not Butter stick.
早料到你会这么说 这是
我不敢相信这不是黄油棒
But Mummy, all the other guys
are going to the Northole.
但妈咪 其他人都去北极啊
I don't care what the
other guys are doing.
我不管其他人干什么
If the other guys jumped in the Bay of Bengal and
tried to swim to Sri Lanka, would you follow them?
如果其他人跳进孟加拉湾 试着
游去斯里兰卡 你会跟着他们吗?
If you were standing
behind me nagging, I might.
要是你在我背后唠叨的话 我会的
Don't talk back to your mother.
别跟你妈顶嘴
This trip is much too dangerous, Rajesh.
这次旅行太危险了 Rajesh
No, it's not. Howard, tell them.
不 不是的 Howard 给他们说说
Doctor and Mrs. Koothrappali, namaste.
Koothrappali博士和夫人 你们好
I undersnd your concern, but if it'll make you
feel any better, my mother is fine with me going,
我理解你们的担忧 这样说
你们会好过点 我妈赞同我去
and this is a woman who kept a
safety rail on my bed until I was 17.
她可是到我17岁时才把
我床上的安全围栏拆下来
So, she has no problem with
her son being eaten by a walrus?
她一点不担心自己儿子被海象吃掉?
That's very unlikely, Mrs. Koothrappali.
这不可能 Koothrappali夫人
If Raj dies, it'll be
from frostbite, gangrene,
如果Raj死了 肯定是由于冻疮 坏疽
acute sunburn or being ripped to
shreds by a 1,500 pound polar bear.
严重晒伤或是被
1500磅的北极熊撕成碎片
Ma, I'm putting you on
speakerphone with Raj's parents.
妈 我打开扬声器
让你和Rajesh的爸妈说说话
Can you tell themthat you're
okay with me going to the Arctic?
能告诉他们你不反对我去北极吗?
Arctic? I thought you said Arkansas!
北极? 我以为你是说阿肯色来着!
I didn't say that.
You never listen to me!
我可没那么说 你从来不仔细听我说!
He doesn't tell me anything!
他没告诉过我任何事!
He lives a secret life
because he's ashamed!
他因为害臊而过着密闭的生活!
Hey, Leonard, can I
talk to you for a sec?
嘿 Leonard 能和你说两句吗?
Sure, but let's go out here where
there's a little less yelling and guilt.
当然 不过我们还是出去说吧
外面没人嚎叫 没罪恶感
What's up?
什么事?
Well, I got yoa little
going away present.
我给你准备了点旅途小礼物
Oh, a blanket.
噢 一条毛毯
Oh, no, no, no, not just a
blanket. See, it has sleeves.
噢 不 不 可不只是一条毯子
瞧 它是有袖子的
Yeah!
不错哦!
So, you can, you know, be all snoodled
up while you do your science stuff.
有了它 当你工作时觉得冷了
就可以把自己包裹的暖暖的了
Oh, wow, cool.
噢 哇哦 真不错
Oh, I'm gonna miss you.
噢 我会想念你的
- See you later.
- Bye.
- 再见
- 拜
I told you no!
我告诉你没有了!
Why don't you believe me?
你怎么就是不信呐?
'Cause it doesn't make sense to me!
因为这完全讲不通!
How can it be thatin the
entire country of India,
怎么可能在偌大一个印度
there isn't one Outback Steakhouse?
都找不到一家澳洲扒座?
(世界连锁的一家西餐屋)
Sheldon... Sheldon?
I want a cookie, Meemaw.
奶奶 我想吃饼干
Sheldon, it's me.
Sheldon 是我
But Meemaw just made cookies.
但我奶奶刚做好了曲奇饼干
Listen, I don't know if I
can go on the expedition.
听我说 我不知道能不能去北极
What?
什么?
I don't think I can
go to the North Pole.
我想我不能去了
Okay, Leonard, I know you're
concerned about disappointing me
好吧 Leonard 我知道你是在担心
你的表现会让我失望
but I want you to take comfort from the knowledge
that my expectations of you are very low.
但这么说吧 可以让你安心点
其实我对你的期望值是非常低的
Yeah, that's very comforting.
是啊 这可真是安抚了我
Comforting is a part of leadership.
安抚也算一种领导才能
It's not a part I care
for, but such is my burden.
虽然不是我非常在意的 但该做还是得做
Terrific, it's just that I
don't think Penny wants me to go.
很好 我只是想说Penny
好像并不想让我去
Assuming that's a valid reason not to
go, wch it isn't, how do you know this?
就算这是你不去的正当理由...显然也不是
你怎么知道她不想你去呢?
- Did she say it?
- Not exactly.
- 她这么说了吗?
- 那倒没有
But she said she was gonna
miss me and she gave me this.
但她说她会想念我的 还给了我这个
What is it?
这是什么?
It's a blanket with sleeves.
是一个有袖子的毯子
Oh, that's clever.
哇 真聪明啊
Let me see if I
understand this correctly.
看看我理解的对不
Her missing you is an emotional
state you find desirable?
她对你的想念之情是你所希望的吧?
- Yes, obviously.
- All right.
- 对 显然
- 好吧
Well, given that missing you
is predicated on you leaving,
那么 既然思念是要以你离开为前提
logic dictates you must leave.
逻辑上来说是你必须离开
Yes, okay, but I'm gonna
be gone for three months.
好吧 但是我要走三个月呢
What if she doesn't miss me that
long and she meets someone else?
如果她不能想念我这么长时间
她遇到了别人呢?
She does have a short attention span.
她的注意力是有点涣散
- So, I can't .
- Leonard, you may be right.
- 所以 我不能走
- Leonard 也许你是对的
It appears that Penny secretly wants you in
her life in a very intimate and carnal fashion.
看起来Penny内心希望你是她生活一部分
非常亲密又有肉体接触的那种
You really think so?
你真这么认为?
Of course not.
当然不是
Even in my sleep-deprived state, I've managed
to pull off another one of my classic pranks.
即使是在我缺乏睡眠的状态下
我还是成功上演了经典忽悠之作啊
Bazinga!
砰玟!
Oh, Leonard, what time is it?
噢 Leonard 现在几点了?
It's 7:00 a.m.I'm sorry it's early,
早晨7点 很抱歉吵醒你了
but we're leaving soon,
and I needed to talk to you.
但我们马上要走了 我要和你谈谈
Okay.
好吧
What did you mean when you
said you're going to miss me?
你当时说你会想我是什么意思?
Um, I don't know.
呃嗯 我不知道
You'll be gone and I'll notice.
你要走了 我会注意到这一点
Okay, well, um, what about
this? What does this mean?
好吧 那么 这个是怎么回事?
这代表什么呢?
Wine, credit card and late night
television are a bad combination.
我想是酒精作用 信用卡账单和
深夜电视混在一起的"杰作"?
All right, fine. What about that
really long hug? What did that mean?
好吧 那那个长时间的拥抱呢? 代表什么?
That wasn't a long hug.
那拥抱时间可不长
It was at least five Mississippis.
至少是5个密西西比了
A standard hug is two Mississippis tops.
标准拥抱是两个密西西比长 顶多了
Leonard, I don't know what to
tell you. It was just a hug.
Leonard 我不知道怎么说 不过是个拥抱
- Glad we cleared that up.
- Yeah.
- 很高兴我们把话说清楚了
- 是的
I guess I'll see you.
我想我该走了
- Okay, have a safe trip.
- Thank you.
- 好的 一路顺风
- 谢谢
- Bye.
- Okay, bye.
- 再见
- 好的 拜
It means I wish you weren't going.
那代表我希望你不要走
- Damn it.
- What?
- 该死的
- 怎么了?
We're out of ice.
没冰块儿了
All right, men, we begin initial assembly
and deployment of the testing equipment
好了 各位 我们明早7点正准时开始
starting tomorrow at 0700 hours,
组装和部署测试设备
but until then, you are all off duty.
在那之前 你们都可以先休息
I suggest you keep the shenanigans to a minimum
as medical help is 18 hours away by dogsled.
我希望你们最好不要搞恶作剧
因为乘雪橇 医疗救助要18小时才能到达
- What are you working on?
- Crossbow.
- 你在干什么?
- 练十字弓
Hey, guys, can I just say something?
嘿 伙计们 听我说
How about we take a moment to
think about where we are right now?
想想我们现在在哪儿好吗?
This is literally the top of the world.
这里可是真正的世界之巅
Only a handful of people in all of human
history will ever see what we are going to see.
这世上只有极一小撮人
能看到我们即将看到的东西
He's right.
他说的对
- Yeah, wow.
- It is remarkable.
- 是啊 哇噢!
- 这太了不起了
So, who's up for a movie?
那么 谁要看电影?
Good idea, what do you think?
好主意 你们想看什么
Ice Station Zebra or John
Carpenter's The Thing?
还是?
- I say double feature.
- Dinner's ready!
- 我建议两场联播
- 晚餐好了!
What are we having?
我们今天吃什么?
Reconstituted Thai food.
冲调性泰国菜
- Did you bring the dehydrated
low-sodium**? - Check.
- 你带了脱水低钠酱汁吗?
- 瞧
- Freezeried spicy mustard?
- Check.
- 冷冻香辣芥末?
- 有
Flash-frozen brown rice, not white?
速冻糙米呢 不是白米?
Uh, oh, sorry.
呃 噢 抱歉
Not to worry. I hid it.
别担心 我藏起来了
Bazinga!
砰砰浜!
You're in my spot.
你坐在我的座儿上了
There's no time for a
crossbow. Find me an icicle.
没时间练十字弓了 快给我找一冰锥子
Three months. This is gonna be great!
三个月 赞啊!
生活大爆炸第二季。本季完。感谢收看。
双语制作:徐小帆
欢迎访问我的博客：http://phjs.me